[{"id": "5eb73cea5e259d7869087332", "question": "A \"waltz-length\" dress stops at what part of the body?", "answer": "The calf", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa82", "question": "In which large bay would you find the Belcher Islands?", "answer": "Hudson Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d68", "question": "In the Bible, who is the mother of the prophet Samuel?", "answer": "Hannah", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be25", "question": "In 2001, what surpassed tuna as America's most eaten seafood?", "answer": "Shrimp", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a82e", "question": "Pashto is the official language of which country?", "answer": "Afghanistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff7bc2e2b316f4693fb678b", "question": "Who explores wild cave systems?", "answer": "A spelunker (The term refers to an untrained amateur.)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c38c", "question": "What metal is the essential ingredient in a dental amalgam filling?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a980", "question": "What Danish peninsula lent its name to the largest naval battle of World War I?", "answer": "Jutland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b278", "question": "During one of his famous freedom-of-speech cases, who wore an American flag to court as a diaper?", "answer": "Larry Flynt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d14", "question": "What story by Mark Twain involves the characters Tom Canty and Edward, Prince of Wales?", "answer": "The Prince and the Pauper", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339833", "question": "What movie, set in Vietnam, won an Oscar for \"Best Picture\" in 1987?", "answer": "Platoon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab96", "question": "What sea is located between Asia Minor and Greece?", "answer": "Aegean Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca0a", "question": "If you have singultus, what do you suffer from?", "answer": "Hiccups", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7ccad877e98cb97778a29", "question": "What is the capital city of American Samoa, a group of islands in the South Pacific?", "answer": "Pogo pogo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5e72d1aad0874f1a5e2d1c2c", "question": "What band has the most No. 1 hits on \"The Billboard Hot 100\" with 20 songs to reach No. 1?", "answer": "The Beatles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b80c", "question": "What sport has a hooker in a scrum?", "answer": "Rugby", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffcfb219dc5ec6cd98a8314", "question": "What popular artist's work has been stolen more than any other's?", "answer": "Picasso has had more of his paintings stolen than any other artist. The Art Loss Register has 550 of his works listed as missing.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c11", "question": "In what year was comedian Stephen Colbert born?", "answer": "1964", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59071c8a3745b36be73039cd", "question": "What is the name of the first space launch facility?", "answer": "Baikonur Cosmodrome", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a479", "question": "In which Irish city is Shannon airport?", "answer": "Shannon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b32341abf195a31e15d73a2", "question": "What desert covers most of southern Mongolia?", "answer": "The Gobi desert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5ab", "question": "Which company is the largest manufacturer of tires?", "answer": "Lego", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2a3", "question": "What does the Roman numeral C represent?", "answer": "100", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be7e", "question": "In 2006, what quarterback became the last USFL veteran to play in an NFL game?", "answer": "Doug Flutie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d81", "question": "Whose paintings include \"The Red Room\", \"The Green Stripe\", \"The Blue Nudes\" and \"The Yellow Odalisque\"?", "answer": "Henri Matisse's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b31c", "question": "Who was the 13th President of the United States of America?", "answer": "Millard Fillmore", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af4f", "question": "During the 20th Century, in what year did the annexation of Austria by German take place?", "answer": "1938", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c4a", "question": "At what age did Robert Downey Jr. study ballet in England?", "answer": "10", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e8021ede59ea584496fe95", "question": "What is a group of squirrels called?", "answer": "Dray or a scurry", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339564", "question": "Which famous muscleman directed the 1992 made-for-TV movie, Christmas in Connecticut?", "answer": "Arnold Schwarzenegger", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cfc", "question": "Who wrote \"Memoirs of a Geisha\"?", "answer": "Arthur Golden", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dbf", "question": "Whose garden is infiltrated by Peter Rabbit?", "answer": "Mr. McGregor's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad0e", "question": "Attila the Hun was the leader of which ancient empire?", "answer": "The Hunnic Empire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefc4dd6ce05a3942286f38", "question": "What is the name of the fishing boat that is featured in the film \"The Perfect Storm\"?", "answer": "Andrea Gail", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8c6", "question": "What is the most common Scrabble letter?", "answer": "E", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1b8", "question": "In 2005, Bhutan became the first country to entirely ban what?", "answer": "Tobacco", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c64c", "question": "A duck-billed platypus is one of the only three mammals in the world that can do what?", "answer": "Lay eggs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd66d94a5bfecdd737e08a3", "question": "What was the most popular month for weddings in the U.S. in 2019?", "answer": "October", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5cb70e1ff96e155acab35d38", "question": "What year was the famous boxing match, dubbed the \"Thrilla in Manila\", held?", "answer": "1975", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a574", "question": "What is the largest bay in Rhode Island?", "answer": "Narragansett Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a162a1bf01ec323f8491721", "question": "What novel by Geoffrey Household was about an attempt to kill Hitler?", "answer": "Rogue Male", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a1e", "question": "What period preceded Picasso's \"Rose Period\"?", "answer": "Blue Period", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5c62b8ab0ae4aacefc17eee2", "question": "Metallica released what song on the album \"Mission: Impossible 2\"?", "answer": "I Disappear", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c8d", "question": "What violinist-bandleader was the first inductee into the Canadian Music Hall of Fame?", "answer": "Guy Lombardo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c87c", "question": "What chemical element has an extra syllable in its more correct British pronunciation?", "answer": "Aluminium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2b4", "question": "Who on TV played Jeeves to Hugh Laurie's Bertie Wooster?", "answer": "Stephen Fry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6ac", "question": "Moroccan stews are cooked and served in a pot called what?", "answer": "Tagine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601217d863c99d48cd169aeb", "question": "What dog breed has a name that translates to \"little brushwood dog\"?", "answer": "Shiba Inu", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f6e97a9e54d890926f6c7", "question": "Just off the coast of Venezuela, one will find Aruba, Bonaire, and Cura\u00e7ao, collectively known as what?", "answer": "The three islands are collectively known as the ABC Islands, or Dutch Antilles.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b737", "question": "London's Old Bailey is a what?", "answer": "Criminal court", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338edc", "question": "What famous horse belonged to Gandalf?", "answer": "Shadowfax", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a38f", "question": "What is the nothernmost provincial capital?", "answer": "Edmonton", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f5649133a95c66dc4fe74f", "question": "Roman Polanski directed which 1974 film starring Jack Nicholson?", "answer": "Chinatown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a896", "question": "What city is home to the Milad Tower?", "answer": "Tehran", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1fe", "question": "What is Pat Benatar's birth name?", "answer": "Patricia Mae Andrzejewski", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfb9", "question": "What is Lepidopterology the study of?", "answer": "Moths and butterflies", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6000f0ee9a72b906b34e3cfe", "question": "Which part of a cow does chuck meat come from?", "answer": "Shoulder", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58d118bc4fea7fe947a22287", "question": "How many successive Wimbledon titles did Bjorn Borg win?", "answer": "5", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1a7", "question": "In what year did the San Francisco 49ers become the first five-time Super Bowl champs?", "answer": "1995", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a406", "question": "Where in Canada would you find Mount Queen Elizabeth?", "answer": "Banff National Park", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fb1", "question": "Comedy band Tenacious D took its name from what sportcaster's catchphrase for good defence?", "answer": "Marv Albert's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fde4966c6c6b019850c9a6f", "question": "Easter was named from what Anglo-Saxon goddess?", "answer": "Eostre", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339577", "question": "What is Scrooge's first name?", "answer": "Ebenezer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd96e2b23c87fd04dd15e34", "question": "What is the oldest sport in history?", "answer": "Wrestling", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5937eed008d98002fdd633d8", "question": "From which musical did \"One Night in Bangkok Makes a Hard Man Humble\" and \"I Know Him So Well\" come?", "answer": "Chess", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133913b", "question": "What year marked the appearance of Doc Savage?", "answer": "1933", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a9c", "question": "In 1984, who became the first African-American US presidential candidate ever to win a primary?", "answer": "Jesse Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f53", "question": "Who is Dinah, whom Alice thinks about nostalgically as she falls down the rabbit hole to Wonderland?", "answer": "Her cat", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7da", "question": "What kind of an animal is the \"horny toad\"?", "answer": "A lizard", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca6d", "question": "Quercus is the Latin name of what tree?", "answer": "Oak", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aca6", "question": "Which is the 28th US state?", "answer": "Texas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bda3", "question": "What Australian snack is made from the yeast extract left over from making beer?", "answer": "Vegemite", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4f5", "question": "Which blood type is a universal donor?", "answer": "O negative", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fc9", "question": "Who is the Norse god of verility, prosperity, and sun?", "answer": "Frey", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdbb", "question": "What animal was used in British coal mines until being phased out in 1986?", "answer": "Canaries", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339226", "question": "What country provided most of the settings for \"The Lord of the Rings\" movies?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339336", "question": "What was the title of the TV series \"M*A*S*H\" theme song?", "answer": "Suicide is Painless", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0b3", "question": "In what year did the Chicago Black Hawks win their first Stanley Cup?", "answer": "1934", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a3e", "question": "How many children did Rob and Laura Petrie have on \"The Dick Van Dyke Show\"?", "answer": "One", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea380fff048f679a45ab20", "question": "What is the scientific name for the job or role an organism plays in its habitat?", "answer": "Niche", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133983a", "question": "Who won a Grammy Award for his album \"Come Dance With Me\"?", "answer": "Frank Sinatra", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c852fbde8045e48466d6", "question": "When was the idea of the atom first introduced?", "answer": "Around\u00a0450 B.C. --  Leucippus and his pupil, Democritus, theorized that matter was composed bits of matter too small to be seen.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c83e", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find Bowman's capsules?", "answer": "The kidneys", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ccf7944b37b32637bdc44bd", "question": "Who was Cesare Borgia's father?", "answer": "Pope Alexander VI", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a471", "question": "What is the capital of Barbados?", "answer": "Bridgetown", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ad9dc04e748bb36357acdda", "question": "What is the name of the ship Darwin sailed on when he made his historic visit to the Gal\u00e1pagos Islands?", "answer": "H.M.S Beagle", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffb59a85dad637d903c8813", "question": "In which Alaskan town do almost all residents live in the same building?", "answer": "In the small town of Whittier, Alaska, almost all residents live in the same building \u2014 a property called Begich Towers", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c76c", "question": "What explorer introduced chickens to the New World?", "answer": "Christopher Columbus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339648", "question": "What was the nickname of Gene Hackman's character in The French Connection?", "answer": "Popeye", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3cd", "question": "What was the nationallity of Rasputin?", "answer": "Russian", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58c89d23011619dd6d415483", "question": "What disappeared from the town of South Park, forcing Randy to relocate his family to a refugee camp in California?", "answer": "The Internet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c618", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Hydrogen?", "answer": "H", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600784b0bd51d85e222ab65d", "question": "Who said, \"Champagne should be dry, cold, and free\".?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c30f", "question": "Theobromine, a substance found in what aphrodisiac, is poisonous to dogs?", "answer": "Chocolate", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e75", "question": "What superteam includes Robin, Kid Flash, Aqualad and Wonder Girl?", "answer": "The Teen Titans", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fede0326ce05a3942286db7", "question": "Which is the only team in NFL history to have scored three touchdowns in less than a minute?", "answer": "New England Patriots", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4de3306d333868d34d710", "question": "What name is given to Britain\u2019s policy of avoiding strict enforcement of parliamentary laws on early American colonies?", "answer": "Salutary neglect", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f3", "question": "What is Tchaikovsky's ballet \"Le Lac des Cygnes\" commonly called?", "answer": "Swan Lake", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8ab1201dd7bf43be5e763", "question": "What is a credenza?", "answer": "A dining sideboard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fdf", "question": "Tchaikovsky is considered to have died of which disease?", "answer": "Cholera", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe77372eec85e375820b308", "question": "Which two oceans are connected by the Drake Passage?", "answer": "Atlantic and Pacific", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab39", "question": "Belgrade lies on the Danube and which other river?", "answer": "Sava", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58d1184b4fea7fe947a22283", "question": "What is the correct name for brown coal?", "answer": "Lignite", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390c9", "question": "What French playwright wrote the play \"The Lark\"?", "answer": "Jean Anouilh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bce9", "question": "According to the ad, how many licks does it take to get to the center of a Tootsie Pop?", "answer": "Three", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c961877e98cb977789f4", "question": "Which state boasts the world's largest flat-top mountain?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133943b", "question": "What brand of motorcycle does Tom Cruise ride in the 1986 movie \"Top Gun\"?", "answer": "Kawasaki", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b41", "question": "What was the short lived game show that Betty White won an Emmy award for hosting in 1983?", "answer": "Just Men!", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0b0", "question": "Which fictional park is the home of Yogi Bear?", "answer": "Jellystone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff2588c31a458464a93c467", "question": "What does the Slavic word \"vodka\" translate to in English?", "answer": "\"Little water\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ec247b8dc25ca9e12ef638", "question": "Cinnabar is the most common source for which compound?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2dc", "question": "Who was Arthur Jefferson's comedy partner?", "answer": "Oliver Hardy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b37e", "question": "The Mason-Dixon line ran between Maryland and which other American State?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fec", "question": "According to a famous SNL catchphrase, what's the only prescription for Christopher Walken's fever?", "answer": "More cowbell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cacf", "question": "What is the study of the Sun called?", "answer": "Heliology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59da1bcaf6756c9b30ba14fe", "question": "Graham Kerr became famous under what nickname?", "answer": "The Galloping Gourmet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdffcb41cf6db9ac4808d02", "question": "Which U.S. city is known as \"The Emerald City\"?", "answer": "Seattle", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58be2ceb8faf425cf37add79", "question": "Lobamba and Mbabane are the legislative and administrative capitals of which African country?", "answer": "Swaziland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fede1f96ce05a3942286dc9", "question": "Which \"Margaritaville\" singer was born on Christmas in 1946?", "answer": "Jimmy Buffett", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fbaed2f0738315b1fb74e2f", "question": "In what year did the first president of Kenya, Jomo Kenyatta, die?", "answer": "1978", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391dc", "question": "Who played Mr. White in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Harvey Keitel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a79", "question": "What ethologist told the story of Elsa the lioness in the book \"Born Free\"?", "answer": "Joy Adamson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1f8", "question": "What year did Volkswagen introduce the Golf R32 model?", "answer": "2002", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b90a", "question": "What year did the famous Sears Tower in Chicago had its name changed to the \"Willis Tower\"?", "answer": "2009", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0f6", "question": "What American was named captain of the Montreal Canadiens in Sep 2015?", "answer": "Max Pacioretty", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bffe", "question": "In popular culture, what is a \"Tamagotchi\"?", "answer": "Virtual pet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d65", "question": "Who played the role of TV's A. J. Soprano?", "answer": "Robert Iler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd81cadd0de9af39e9d4687", "question": "The Oregon Trail started in what city?", "answer": "Independence, Missouri", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7ee", "question": "On what continent is Mt. Vesuvius?", "answer": "Europe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5977442d284458f1d785442d", "question": "The original name of New York City was what?", "answer": "New Amsterdam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a946", "question": "In what country is the Bataan Peninsula?", "answer": "The Philippines", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133943f", "question": "What song do the soldiers sing walking through the rubble of Hue in the movie Full Metal Jacket?", "answer": "The Mickey Mouse Club theme", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefc29f6ce05a3942286f1b", "question": "In the Clint Eastwood film, \"The Dead Pool,\" who plays the roll of Johnny Squares?", "answer": "Jim Carrey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c048", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of India?", "answer": "Indian Peacock", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c495", "question": "What vitamin group is mostly required for blood coagulation?", "answer": "Vitamin K", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133913a", "question": "What is the full name of the fictional character Doc Savage?", "answer": "Clark Savage, Jr.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59523d2a736d4be723796b3e", "question": "Musician Drake first gained popularity appearing on which teen TV show?", "answer": "Degrassi: The Next Generation", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca8d", "question": "In what year was nylon first synthesized?", "answer": "1935", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bed4", "question": "How many camels carried the 117,000 volumes of Abdul Kassem Ismael's library?", "answer": "400", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58be2d418faf425cf37add7c", "question": "The American rock band, \"The Black Keys\", hails from which US state?", "answer": "Ohio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad8d", "question": "Who crossed the Delaware River on Christmas Eve in 1776 to catch the German Hessians celebrating Christmas?", "answer": "Gen. Washington", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8b44d01dd7bf43be5e7be", "question": "Where is the U.S. vice president's official residence?", "answer": "United States Naval Observatory", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e6f", "question": "Who played the blind character in the movie \"Tommy\"?", "answer": "Roger Daltry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefc10d6ce05a3942286f0d", "question": "Who recorded the song \"Private Eyes\"?", "answer": "Hall and Oates", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfb7", "question": "Which building material gets its name from Arabic for \"brick\"?", "answer": "Adobe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59f9bbce364247bf200fb8a8", "question": "Lusaka is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Zambia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c1cc877e98cb9777897d", "question": "What does Salzburg translate to?", "answer": "Salt Castle", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef96e56ce05a3942286ea3", "question": "In the first televised baseball game, the Cincinnati Reds played what team?", "answer": "Brooklyn Dodgers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a14d", "question": "Which female singer collaborated with Eminem for the song \"Stan\"?", "answer": "Dido", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c75f", "question": "In what year did the Soviet Union launch its first Sputnik satellite?", "answer": "1957", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b709", "question": "What is Santa Claus more commonly called in Britain?", "answer": "Father Christmas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "593c4b5db8198b9a2b077963", "question": "The film \"Casablanca\" takes place during which war?", "answer": "World War II", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339245", "question": "What is the birth country of Russell Crowe?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66be9a5bfecdd737e088b", "question": "What's the name of the punctuation that combines a question mark and an exclamation point?", "answer": "Interrobang", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a077", "question": "In the TV series \"Leave It To Beaver\", what was Wally's best friend's name?", "answer": "Eddie Haskell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b292", "question": "What piece of technology did IBM develop in 1973 that they nicknamed Winchester?", "answer": "A disk drive", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5902a066cad1ec93f27df76a", "question": "Which Bohemian city gave us the Pilsner?", "answer": "Pilsen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390e5", "question": "What nationality was writer Arthur C. Clarke?", "answer": "British", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdb1", "question": "Which ingredient provides the red color in a Tequila Sunrise?", "answer": "Grenadine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1b0", "question": "In 2001, who gave the first concert in Oslo's Vallhall football arena?", "answer": "A-ha", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0b5", "question": "The March of Dimes was originally founded to help find a vaccine for what?", "answer": "Polio", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beb3", "question": "Which cuisine gave us kimchi and bulgogi?", "answer": "Korean", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d06", "question": "In what 1949 novel is the world divided into three principal continents: Oceania, Eurasia, Eastasia?", "answer": "1984", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b66", "question": "Who created Bugs Bunny?", "answer": "Tex Avery", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab94", "question": "In what present-day country is Mount Ararat located?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58c8a8b090aac110e4167091", "question": "In the North American market, what is the difference between hard and sweet cider?", "answer": "Hard cider is alcoholic while sweet cider is not", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ded21eea2747c8aff16d3a", "question": "Which 19th century French artist painted \"Bathers at Asnieres\"?", "answer": "Georges Seurat", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395c0", "question": "In The Simpsons, who is Cletus, the slack-jawed yokel married to?", "answer": "Brandine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede60a6ce05a3942286df4", "question": "On what avenue does the traditional New York City Easter Parade and Bonnet Festival take place?", "answer": "Fifth Avenue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b60", "question": "What 1970's TV series was revived in 2007 with Michelle Ryan in the title role?", "answer": "Bionic Woman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd8f", "question": "What was originally sold in 1965 under the name \"Chemgrass\"?", "answer": "AstroTurf", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe773bceec85e375820b30c", "question": "How many \"emirates\" make up the United Arab Emirates?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefc1b36ce05a3942286f13", "question": "In the \"Captain America: The Winter Soldier\" film, who was Winter Soldier?", "answer": "Bucky Barnes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c848", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the Sertoli cells?", "answer": "The testes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b27f", "question": "What word did Alexander Graham Bell suggest for answering the phone?", "answer": "Ahoy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea3c8aff048f679a45ab40", "question": "Chromophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Colors", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e699fe83fe1f2a824bcf", "question": "Which pioneer of hair products became America\u2019s first black female millionaire?", "answer": "Sarah Breedlove \u2013 who later became known as Madam CJ Walker", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c300", "question": "Which elephant can't be domesticated, the African or Indian?", "answer": "The African", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3c3", "question": "What is the name for a baby turkey?", "answer": "Poult", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fec8717ec223966ae8f8812", "question": "The Doak Walker Award is given annually to the top college player at which position?", "answer": "Running Back", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b019", "question": "Prior to Ronald Reagan, who was the last US president whose first and last name began with the same letter?", "answer": "Herbert Hoover", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb0a", "question": "Are pumpkins fruits or vegetables?", "answer": "Fruits", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c63", "question": "Who directed the Indiana Jones movies released in the 1980s?", "answer": "Steven Spielberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133938e", "question": "Who played the role of Jim Stark in the movie \"Rebel Without a Cause\"?", "answer": "James Dean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8f2", "question": "What sport in the Olympics includes tucks, twists and pikes?", "answer": "Diving", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeeb", "question": "Which U.S. President ended his country's participation in the Vietnam War?", "answer": "Richard Nixon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b591", "question": "What does the abbreviation MBA stand for in the MBA master's degree designation?", "answer": "Master of Business Administration", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cff", "question": "What category of writing are the Hugo Awards given for?", "answer": "Science-fiction", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9b8", "question": "The Province of Saskatchewan shares its southern border with which two US states?", "answer": "Montana and North Dakota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc39", "question": "What do the initials in O.J. Simpson's name stand for?", "answer": "Orenthal James", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe939506bd93ce3a4e5f68b", "question": "What plant do scientists use to clean up radioactive waste?", "answer": "Sunflowers", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6af", "question": "What do climbers rub on their hands for extra grip?", "answer": "Chalk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd15", "question": "What is called the \"bark lion sentinel dog\" in its native Tibet?", "answer": "The Lhasa apso", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dbc", "question": "In what 1863 short story does Philip Nolan renounce his US citizenship?", "answer": "The Man Without a Country", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bc0", "question": "David Bowie is known for his distinct voice type?", "answer": "Baritone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6f4", "question": "How many sides does a trapezoid have?", "answer": "4", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd6a2106c0f9723ab15cb3e", "question": "How many constellations are there in the sky?", "answer": "48 traditional Western constellations", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339deb", "question": "What was the name of Willie Tyler's dummy?", "answer": "Lester", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339162", "question": "Who created the popular cartoon TV show \"The Simpsons\"?", "answer": "Matt Groening", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4b8", "question": "\"Video Killed the Radio Star\" was the debut music video on which channel in 1981?", "answer": "MTV", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b57", "question": "Whose autobiography was entitled \"The Long Walk to Freedom\"?", "answer": "Nelson Mandela", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "594d06211a1c922dd1ac64a8", "question": "What year did Robert A. Heinlein published the novel \"The Number of the Beast\"?", "answer": "1980", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133becd", "question": "How many Witches are in a coven?", "answer": "13", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4b67206d333868d34d6f1", "question": "Twenty-two months of negotiation and the 1998 Good Friday Agreement ended violence in what nation?", "answer": "Northern Ireland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aedb", "question": "In which present-day country is the site of the battle of Waterloo?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396dc", "question": "What alien comes from the planet Melmac?", "answer": "Alf", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339704", "question": "Which Star Trek character is a big fan of Earl Grey tea?", "answer": "Captain Picard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd27", "question": "In Europe, what are measured in \"Paris Points\"?", "answer": "Shoe sizes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339764", "question": "What is the name of the Warden in Chicago?", "answer": "Matron 'Mama' Morton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d2942596a59cbdfbd390", "question": "Who has won the most Oscars?", "answer": "Katherine Hepburn (4)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb30", "question": "What is your occupation if you are sometimes referred to as an apiarist?", "answer": "Beekeeper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389d1", "question": "Who wrote \"Charlie and the Chocolate Factory\"?", "answer": "Roald Dahl", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa3f57c73aa70ea0b70afe", "question": "Which U.S. state has the unofficial motto \"May The 14th Star Shine Bright\"?", "answer": "Vermont (The unofficial motto \u201cStella Quarta Decima Fulgeat\u201d was adopted in 2015 after being proposed by a Vermonter Latin student.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b39f", "question": "Who is the inventor of the cash register?", "answer": "James Ritty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd7f", "question": "What spice is named for the capital of French Guiana?", "answer": "Cayenne pepper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fcf", "question": "What TV show did \"A Different World\" spin off from?", "answer": "The Cosby Show", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6018bc96d96d05b23b281658", "question": "At which hospital did the first heart transplant take place?", "answer": "Groote Schuur Hospital, Cape Town, South Africa", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392b3", "question": "What TV show premiered in 1974 and opened each week with an answering machine playing a different message?", "answer": "The Rockford Files", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59008f8ecf842fa4c4ba96be", "question": "Who is the Roman Patron Saint of hangovers?", "answer": "Saint Bibiana", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392e5", "question": "In \"Rocky 3\" what does Apollo Creed give as a gift before he fights \"Clubber\" Lang?", "answer": "Boxing trunks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8ef8601dd7bf43be5e7f3", "question": "What pasta gets its name because of its resemblance to a feather quill?", "answer": "Penne", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab0a2dbaab681b09292165", "question": "Who won the first season of American Idol?", "answer": "Kelly Clarkson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6bc", "question": "What type of pasta is usually shaped like little wagon wheels?", "answer": "Rotelle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb659c5dad637d903c8835", "question": "Queen Alexandra's father and brother were kings of what country?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c2f", "question": "Who voiced Snow White in the 1937 movie \"Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs\"?", "answer": "Adriana Caselotti", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa23", "question": "Which country has Budapest as its capital?", "answer": "Hungary", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef5f306ce05a3942286e3f", "question": "Who died tragically young outside L.A.'s Viper Room club?", "answer": "River Phoenix", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c90d62c52800b05cac20f1f", "question": "What two planets in our Solar System possess no moons?", "answer": "Mercury and Venus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600241ec4be4723ccac2217f", "question": "Which author wrote the spy novel \"Tinker, Tailor, Soldier, Spy\"?", "answer": "John Le Carre", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0df", "question": "Who is Snoopy's arch enemy?", "answer": "The Red Baron", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6018bcb0d96d05b23b28165a", "question": "Who was murdered along with OJ Simpson\u2019s estranged wife Nicole?", "answer": "Ronald Goldman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8cf", "question": "Where was the first mobile automaton, named \"Beast\", built in?", "answer": "John Hopkins University", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396c2", "question": "Who does Bruce Banner turn into when he gets angry?", "answer": "The Hulk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0f1", "question": "What is Ray Charles' real last name?", "answer": "Robinson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe909b101dd7bf43be5e890", "question": "What is the outside covering of a plant's root called?", "answer": "Root epidermis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ddd", "question": "Who reveals \"the man behind the curtain\" in \"The Wizard of Oz\"?", "answer": "Toto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394b3", "question": "What city did the Solomons call home in the TV show \"3rd Rock from the Sun\"?", "answer": "Rutherford, Ohio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a7cf20565ad31a57c7ef", "question": "What was the first US state to pass a law requiring mandatory seat belt use?", "answer": "New York", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6990a20565ad31a57c73f", "question": "What legendary athlete lit the Olympic torch at the 1996 Atlanta Olympics?", "answer": "Mohammed Ali", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad5a", "question": "What president delivered his \"Fourteen Points\" speech in Congress in 1918?", "answer": "Woodrow Wilson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc7f", "question": "To counter slipping sales, what was marketed, beginning in 1987, as \"the other white meat\"?", "answer": "Pork", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133898f", "question": "What war provides the background for the book \"Gone with the Wind\"?", "answer": "The Civil War", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fec88b4ec223966ae8f8822", "question": "The peripheral device that could be used to connect two Gameboys was called what?", "answer": "Game Link Cable", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133960f", "question": "What 2005 movie stars Ellen Page and Sandra Oh?", "answer": "Hard Candy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909d1dfbb53d1af65886504", "question": "What American soul singer-songwriter died on December 25, 2006?", "answer": "James Brown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1cd", "question": "What did Pieter van Musschenbroek create at a namesake Dutch university in 1746 by lining a glass jar with silver foil?", "answer": "The Leyden jar", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6b4", "question": "What fruit is normally squeezed into a margarita?", "answer": "Lime", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7ab", "question": "Tornadoes are columns of air that generally come into contact with what kind of clouds?", "answer": "Cumulonimbus cloud", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a536", "question": "What mountain chain runs from Maine to Alabama?", "answer": "Appalachian Mountains", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0ba", "question": "Which French salad containing tuna, anchovies, tomatoes, olives and hard boiled eggs?", "answer": "Salade nicoise", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e3d", "question": "What is the title object of the 2006 film \"Brick\" a brick of?", "answer": "Heroin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b304", "question": "What title was given to Nanak, the founder of Sikhism?", "answer": "Guru", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b358c2c5db0d66a186cb55b", "question": "Popular in the Balkans, what type of beverage is the \"Rakia\"?", "answer": "Fruit brandy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60121a9563c99d48cd169b04", "question": "What is the common name for enuresis?", "answer": "Bedwetting", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e6bc59fb6c85e9e634ff5c", "question": "Who sang \"All I Wanna Do\"?", "answer": "Sheryl Crow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7df", "question": "In which US state is Shenandoah National Park located?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}]